What is available?
Well, depth-first search
you may have heard of.
Depth-first search is
available to you.
So I like to think of the search tree,
you can think of it like a big
mountain, right?
And in a way, this is misleading.
Because the mountain, it's not
like a normal mountain.
It's exponentially larger the deeper
you go into this mountain, right?
So in general, the bottom of this
mountain is very, very wide.
And depth-first search basically starts
at the top and goes straight
down, but in a very particular way.
So let's take this example, and let's
try depth-first search, straight to
the bottom.
Well, here's the tree.
So in this case I'm, going
to speed this up.
I'm not going to draw the fringe and
cross things off manually, but what
you're going to see here is
on the top is the graph.
On the bottom is the tree, and when I
highlight something in the tree, I'll
also highlight which path it corresponds
to in the graph.
Just remember, nodes in the tree are
paths or plans in the graph.
So the strategy in depth-first search
is expand some deepest node first.
So we've only got one node on our
fringe to begin with, it's s.
So we expand it first.
Now on our fringe is these nodes
that correspond to d, e, and
p, just like before.
Which one does depth-first
search want?
As I've described it, it doesn't care.
They're all equally deep.
They're all equally good.
Specific implementations
will make a choice.
So let's imagine the implementation is
always choosing the one on the left,
and goes through these in
order to break ties.
Well, we take off d.
And now what's on our fringe?
We've got this b, c, and e paths.
We've got another e path that's
shorter, and a p path.
So these five things.
What does depth-first
search want next?
Well, b, c, or e.
And because we're going through
successors in order in this
implementation, we're going
to take the one through b.
And you can see now we'll
go down to a.
Now, we hit the bottom.
You can't go any further from a, and
it's not like we declare failure.
We've still got our fringe, right?
It's still sitting there, and now the
next deepest thing that's left is
this path to c.
So we'll go there.
We'll try again.
That didn't work.
Now we'll go to e.
Notice we're going to be deeper path
to e, not the shallower one.
Because that happens to be the one
we hit first in this order.
Now what's next?
H, then p, then q.
And we kind of continue through until
here we're getting to the goal, so
I'll slow down.
You get here, you see this is not a
goal, and it has no successors.
The next deepest thing on the
fringe, you pop it off.
It's a goal path.
You declare victory, and this
is the path you found.
So let's think about what we just did.
What did we just do?
We basically went straight down
the left of the tree.
Let's just watch the colors.
Don't watch the specific letters.
So just watch how it works.
From left to right.
We're kind of going across this graph,
starting on the left and striping
across kind of vertically.